anovaculinary.com 2019-10-13

# Privacy Policy | Anova Culinary

Anova Privacy Policy EU Privacy Policy

Effective Date: April 23, 2018

Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Statement describes the types of information Anova collects from and about you when you visit our website, www.anovaculinary.com (“Site”), use our mobile applications (each an “App”), or use our sous vide devices (each a “Connected Product”).  The Site, Apps, and Connected Products are collectively the “Services.” This Privacy Statement also explains how Anova may use and disclose such information, as well as your ability to control certain uses of it.

### INFORMATION COLLECTION:

Information You Provide to Us

Anova collects information from you when you choose to provide it to us. This may include when you request information from us, purchase or register a product, submit a rebate form, create an account with us, sign up for newsletters or our email list, use our Services, submit a rating or review, participate in a survey or promotion, or otherwise contact us.

Information You Provide When You Create an Account

You may be required to provide certain personal information to create your Anova account. The personal information we collect may include your name, address, email address, telephone number, geolocation information, and mobile device identifier.

Information You Provide When You Make a Purchase

If you make a purchase from us, we collect a credit/debit card number and related financial information (such as CVV, expiration date, and billing address), or other payment information (such as via PayPal, Google Pay or Apple Pay), depending on the form of payment you choose.

Information You Provide about a Third Party

If you send someone else a communication from the Services, such as sending an invitation to a friend, the information you provide (e.g., name, e-mail address) will be used to facilitate the communication and will not be used for any other marketing purpose, unless such person registers with us or becomes a customer, we obtain consent from such person, or we explicitly say otherwise at the point of collection.

Information You Provide Through Social Media

You may also be given the option to link to your Facebook or other social media account through the Services. When you do, we may automatically receive certain information about you based on your registration and privacy settings on those third party services. This may include, but may not be limited to, name, user name, demographic information, updated address or contact information, location, interests, and publicly-observed data, such as from social media and online activity.

Information We Automatically Collect

We may use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, log files, or other technologies to automatically collect certain information when you use our Service or interact with our emails and online, mobile, and Connected Product advertisements, and to allow Anova to keep track of analytics and certain statistical information. For example, we may automatically collect certain information from you, including but not limited to your browser type, device type, operating system, unique device identifier of any of your computer(s) or device(s) that are used to access the Services, software version, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, geolocation, phone model, phone operating system, and the domain name from which you accessed the Services. We also may collect information about your use of the Services, including the date and time you access the Services, the areas or pages of the Services that you visit, the amount of time you spend using the Services, the number of times you return, whether you open, forward or click-through emails and ads and other Services usage data. 

Third Party Service Providers

We may use third party service providers to support our Services. Some of these service providers may use technology such as cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, log files, and other technologies to receive, collect, and store information. 

Third Party Analytic Technologies

We may use third parties’ analytics and tracking tools to better understand how people are using the Services, how to improve the effectiveness of the Services and related content, and to help us or those third parties serve more targeted advertising to you across the Internet. These tools may use technology such as cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, log files, or other technologies to automatically collect and store certain information. They may also combine information they collect from your interaction with the Services with information they collect from other sources. We do not have access to, or control over, these third parties’ use of cookies or other tracking technologies.

Combination of Information

We may combine the information we receive from and about you, including information you provide to us and information we automatically collect through our Services, as well as information collected offline, across other computers or devices that you may use, and from third party sources.

### INFORMATION USE:

Anova may use the information we collect from and about you to: Respond to your inquiries, fulfill orders, process payments, prevent transactional fraud, provide services, and contact when necessary; Enhance your experience, including as a way to recognize you on the Services; Review the usage and operations of our Service, develop new products or services, and conduct analysis to enhance or improve our content, products, and services; Provide you with customized content, targeted offers, and advertising on the Services, via email, push notificiations or text message, or across other websites, mobile apps, social media or online services; Contact you with information, newsletters and promotional materials from Anova or on behalf of our partners and affiliates; Use your data in an aggregated non-specific format for analytical and demographic purposes; Research, address problems, and improve the operations of our Services; Protect the security or integrity of the Services and our business; and As described to you at the point of data collection.

### INFORMATION SHARING:

Anova may share the information we collect from and about you: Affiliates. Among Anova brands, subsidiaries, and parent companies. Service Providers. To our third party service providers that provide business, professional or technical support functions for us. Sweepstakes, Contests, and Promotions. If you choose to enter into one of our sweepstakes, contests, or other promotions (a “Promotion”) we may disclose your information to third parties or the public in connection with the administration of such Promotion, as required by law, as otherwise permitted by the Promotion’s official rules, or otherwise in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Statement. Legal Matters; Safety. To respond to subpoenas, judicial processes, or government requests and investigations, or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety, as permitted by law, or otherwise as required by law. We may disclose your information to protect the security of our Services, servers, network systems, and databases. We also may disclose your information as necessary, if we believe that there has been a violation of our Terms of Use, any other legal document or contract related to our services, or the rights of any third party. Sale or Transfer of Business or Assets. We may sell or purchase assets during the normal course of our business. If another entity acquires us or any of our assets, information we have collected about you may be transferred to such entity. In addition, if any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding is brought by or against us, such information may be considered an asset of ours and may be sold or transferred to third parties. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to require that the transferee use personal information provided through the Services in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Statement. Aggregate or Anonymous Non-Personal Information. We may also share aggregate, anonymous, or de-identified non-personal information with third parties for their marketing or analytics uses. Other. We also may share your information as described to you at the point of collection.

### YOUR CHOICES AND OPT-OUTS:

Cookies, Tracking Options and California Do Not Track Disclosures Certain parts of our Services require cookies. You are free to set your browser or operating system settings to limit certain tracking or to decline cookies, but by doing so, you may not be able to use certain features on the Services or take full advantage of all of our offerings. Please refer to your Web browser’s or operating system’s website or “Help” section for more information on how to delete and/or disable your browser or operating system from receiving cookies or controlling your tracking preferences.

Our system may not respond to Do Not Track requests or headers from some or all browsers. We may use cookies or other technologies to deliver more relevant advertising and to link data collected across other computers or devices that you may use. To understand your choices for receiving more relevant advertising or to manage your settings, please review the information below:

To learn more about the use of cookies or other technologies to deliver more relevant advertising and to know your choices about the collection and use of data by these third party tools, you may visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s (NAI) opt-out page here.

If you wish to prevent your data from being used by Google Analytics, Google has developed the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on available here.

On your mobile device, you may also adjust your privacy and advertising settings to control whether you want to receive more relevant advertising.

Your Marketing Preferences

To opt out of receiving direct marketing materials, please contact us at 1-877-421-8282 or support@anovaculinary.com You may also opt-out of any direct electronic marketing from Anova by using the unsubscribe information therein.

If you receive marketing communications from one or more Anova affiliates, you must opt-out individually from each of the affiliates from which you are receiving brand-specific marketing communications.

### YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS:

If you are a California resident, you may opt-out of our disclosure of personal information to third parties affiliated companies for their direct marketing purposes. To opt out, please contact us at support@anovaculinary.com or 1-855-421-8282. You must put the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the subject field. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information.

For California residents:  Anova may share your personal information with affiliated third parties, some of which do not share the Anova name, for their direct marketing purposes. As this category of affiliate is considered an unaffiliated party under California law, you may request information about our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us at support@anovaculinary.com or 1-855-421-8282.

### THIRD-PARTY CONTENT, LINKS, AND PLUG-INS:

The Services may have links to third-party websites, which may have privacy policies that differ from our own. We are not responsible for the practices of such sites. 

The Service may also offer you the ability to interact with social plugins from social media sites, which may allow us and/or the social media site to receive data from or about you. In some cases, we may know that you clicked on a social plugin, such as a Twitter Follow button, or receive other information from the social media sites. Similarly, if you have previously provided personal information to a third-party operating a plug-in on the Services, then such third-party may recognize you on the Services. Your use of social network plugins is subject to each social media site’s privacy policy, which may be different from ours, so please read these policies carefully to understand their policies and your options. As with linked sites, we have no control over the information that is collected, stored, or used by social network plugins, and are not responsible for the practices of such sites.

### PUBLIC FORUMS:

Any information you may disclose on our Services, in blogs, on message boards, in chat rooms, or on other public areas on the Services or other third-party websites that this Service may link to, becomes public information. Please exercise caution when disclosing personal information in these public areas. 

### CHILDREN’S PRIVACY:

Protecting children’s privacy is important to us. We do not direct the Services to, nor do we knowingly collect any personal information from, children under the age of thirteen.

### DATA SECURITY:

Anova is committed to maintaining the security of the data you provide us and will take reasonable precautions to help protect your personal information. We have taken certain physical, administrative, and technical steps to safeguard the information we collect from and about our customers and visitors to our Services. Because there is always some risk in transmitting information over the Internet, while we make every effort to help ensure the integrity and security of our network and systems, we cannot guarantee our security measures. 

### DATA STORAGE:

Your personal information is stored on servers in the United States and Europe; however, some of our brands, subsidiaries, parent company, and service providers may store information on servers hosted in other countries. As such, your personal information may be subject to the laws of other countries, where the data protection and other laws may differ from those where you are located. Your personal information may be disclosed in response to inquiries or requests from government authorities or to respond to judicial process in the countries in which we operate.

### IF YOU HAVE QUESTIONS:

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement or the practices described herein, you may contact us at 1-855-421-8282 or support@anovaculinary.com.

### REVISIONS TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT:

Anova reserves the right to revise this Privacy Statement at any time. When we do, we will post the change(s) on the Services. If we change the Privacy Statement in a material way, we will provide appropriate notice to you.

Anova Applied Electronics, Inc.

667 Howard Street

San Francisco, CA 98105

1-855-421-8282

General Requests: [info@anovaculinary.com](mailto:info@anovaculinary.com)

Privacy Email: [privacy@anovaculinary.com](mailto:privacy@anovaculinary.com)

* * *

## PROTECTION OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA

Electrolux is committed to being a trusted and responsible partner for all of its valued customers. This means that we are committed to operating in an open and transparent manner and in compliance with applicable laws and regulations, including providing our customers with up-to-date information about our collection and use of personal data.

We encourage you to read our Data Privacy Statement which details, among other things, what personal data we process about you and for what purposes. It also summarizes what your rights are when it comes to this data.

## DATA PRIVACY STATEMENT

We would like to provide you with information about what information about you (your “ **personal data** ”) that we collect, what we use it for, with whom we share it and what rights you have.

### The types of personal data we collect:

  * **A) Contact** **information** \- such as name, address, phone number, email address, and login information;
  * **B) Information about your purchase of products or services** – such as product registration information, warranty information and enrolment status in services;
  * **C) Consumer satisfaction and feedback** **data** \- such as the results of customer satisfaction and feedback surveys;
  * **D) Data collected when you are visiting our website -** such as data collected through cookies and other automatically collected data to provide you with our websites, or information that you provide us with when visiting our websites (such as through contact forms etc.);
  * **E) Data identifying the appliance  **\- such as PNC number, serial number, software version, MAC address, model, colour etc;
  * **F) Appliance** **usage data** \- such as how and when the appliance is being used (frequency and which cycles)
  * **G) Data generated by the appliance itself** \- such as operating data e.g. opening and closing of internal valves,  heating circuit use and efficiency, oven temperature, motor power, activities driven by the appliance’s software in order to deliver the cycle/function chosen by you; efficiency data e.g. water consumption, energy consumption; situational Data e.g. conditions surrounding the appliance such as ambient temperature, air humidity, water hardness.

### How we collect personal data:

  * from you or your representative when purchasing your product, registering your product, visiting our website, activating your account, ordering a service, participating in our campaigns, creating a product review or when downloading and using an application;
  * from our retailers;
  * from our third party service providers, suppliers and partners;
  * from publicly available sources;
  * from social media, e.g. Facebook if you choose to use Facebook to facilitate logging into our websites/ apps.

You may choose not to provide certain types of personal data to us. If you choose to do so, this may affect our ability to provide you with, and your ability to make use of, certain appliances and/or services or their functionalities and features. However, unless otherwise specified, your choice not to provide such information will not result in legal consequences for you.

We may also combine the personal data you provide to us with other information collected online or offline to the extent permitted by applicable laws, including information provided by third parties, and use or share it for the purposes described in this Data Privacy Statement. We may anonymise the information we collect (meaning that it can no longer be associated to you and hence no longer constitutes personal data).

### Why we process your personal data and the legal basis for the processing

We may use your personal data for the following purposes (collectively “ **Processing Purposes** ”):

**Processing Purposes** ** **

| 

**Type(s) of personal data**

| 

**Legal basis**  
  
---|---|---  
  
To assist in the development, testing, enhancement and modifications of our products and services

| 

Types C, E, F and G above

| 

Legitimate interest to enchance and modify our products and services.  
  
In the event of a contemplated or actual reorganisation, merger, acquisition, sale, joint venture, assignment or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets and stock

| 

Types A, B, C, D, E, F, and G above

| 

Legitimate interest to facilitate and/or enable the contemplated or actual reorganisation, merger, acquisition, sale, joint venture, assignment or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets and stocks.  
  
To send you marketing communications

| 

Your contact information (type A and B above)

| 

Consent or Legitimate interest to market our products and services.  
  
To enable functionality in accordance with the description of the appliance / service

| 

Types A, E, F and G above

| 

Fulfilment of contract  
  
To provide you with products and services you have requested

| 

Types A, C, D, E, F and G above

| 

Fulfilment of contract  
  
To provide you with administrative notices such as user guidance/ product safety notices relating to your appliance,  service or account

| 

Types A, B, E, F and G above

| 

Fulfilment of contract  
  
For troubleshooting and repairing purposes

| 

Types A, E, F and G above

| 

Fulfilment of contract  
  
To communicate with you about your product, service or account and similar customer service related activities

| 

Types A, B, C, D, E, F and G above

| 

Fulfilment of contract or other legitimate purpose, such as to keep you informed about products, services or account  
  
Internal business purposes, including security, analytics, audit, and for our core operational activities

| 

Types A, B, C, D, E, F and G above

| 

Legitimate interest to facilitate and enable us to fulfil our internal business purposes.  
  
To evaluate your feedback when you rate and review our products or services

| 

Type A, C above

| 

Legitimate interest of improving our products.  
  
To manage and operate our websites and applications, including online registration

| 

Types A, B, C, D, E, F and G above

| 

Fulfilment of contract or other legitimate interest such as enhancing user experience.  
  
### Your consent

Where the processing activity is based on your consent, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. The revocation of your consent will however not affect the lawfulness of any processing based on your consent before its withdrawal.

### Information that we share

For the Processing purposes set out above, we may share or disclose your personal data:

  * As required by law, to comply with legal process and/or to respond to requests from public and government authorities;
  * With companies within the Electrolux group;
  * With service providers and suppliers trusted to provide services and appliances on our behalf as well as with our partners;
  * With a third party in the event of a contemplated or actual reorganisation, merger, acquisition, sale, joint venture, assignment or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets and stock;
  * To enforce our terms and conditions; or
  * To protect our rights.

When sharing personal data with a third party, Electrolux requires that such third party agrees to protect and handle your personal data in accordance with all legal, regulatory and contractual obligations, or other instructions we provide to them.

### Your choices regarding marketing and information

You have certain choices regarding how we use and share your personal data for marketing and similar purposes. Subject to your consent, Electrolux may send you information about appliances, services, events and promotions. The communication may be sent via different channels: email, phone, SMS, post, social networks. We would like to provide you with the best experience, therefore the communication might be tailored based on the data collected and your preferences.

Where required by law, we will obtain your prior consent. You may withdraw your consent to marketing at any time For example, you can unsubscribe from messages by following the unsubscribe instructions within the message or go to your online account to update your marketing preferences.

If you choose not to receive marketing communications, your personal data may still be used for the other purposes described in this Data Privacy Statement, such as communicating with you for administrative or transaction purposes as part of the contractual relationship we have with you or where required by law.

### Your rights under EU/EEA law

If you are located in the EU/EEA, or if your personal data is otherwise being processed by an Electrolux entity within the EU/EEA, you have the following rights:

  1. Request access to your personal data;
  2. Rectification of your personal data;
  3. Request the erasure of your personal data;
  4. Restrict the processing of your personal data;
  5. Request that your personal data be provided in a format that can be transferred to you or another organisation (portability);
  6. Object to the processing of your personal data; and
  7. Lodge a complaint with the competent supervisory authority.

If you have any questions regarding these rights, or if you would like to exercise any of these rights, you may do so in writing, by phone or via email.

Please note that exercising these rights may impact our ability to provide you with certain appliances, functionality or services.

### Security of your personal data

Electrolux will take appropriate technical and organizational measures in line with applicable data protection laws, including requiring our service providers, business partners or professional advisors to use appropriate measures to protect your personal data.

### Storage of your personal data

We will store your personal data for as long as may be required by law, or as required under any contract. If there is no legal requirement, we will retain information about you only for so long as is necessary for the purpose/s for which it was collected.

### International transfers

As a global company, we may store your personal data in the European Union (EU) or in the  European Economic Area (EEA) or other locations where we or our service providers and suppliers are located or have servers.

We may transfer your information between Electrolux group companies or transfer information to our international third party service providers and suppliers acting on our behalf, for the purposes described in this Data Privacy Statement.

_Specific information to citizens of the EU/EEA with regard to international transfers  
_ Your information may be transferred to a country outside of the EU/EEA which may not provide the equivalent level of  data protection as the EU/EEA. We provide appropriate safeguards and protections for such cross-border transfers as required by law, including the use of Standard Contractual Clauses approved by the European Commission, Code of Conducts and/or Binding Corporate Rules. You may request a copy of these documents by contacting us at the address below.

### How to contact us

The controller of your personal data is AB Electrolux (publ)

If you want to exercise your data subject rights or if you have any other questions concerning this Data Privacy Statement, please submit your request at [www.electroluxgroup.com/privacy](http://www.electroluxgroup.com/privacy).

For your information, the Data Protection Officer’s contact references are:

AB Electrolux (publ)  
Data Protection Officer  
105 45 Stockholm  
Sweden  
privacy@electrolux.com  

### Updates to this Data Privacy Statement

We may update this Data Privacy Statement.  Any changes to this Data Privacy Statement will become effective as of the date it is published,  or as otherwise required by law.

Last updated on: 22 March, 2018.
